Guide to the Richmond John Rathbone Collection of Rare Maps, 1550-1798
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Richmond John Rathbone Collection of Rare Maps
1550-1798
Rathbone, Richmond John
1.3 cubic feet (1 box, 1 map folder)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Collection of maps, atlas pages, and documents depicting the Western Hemisphere, globe, and regions of North America from the 16th to 18th centuries. Also included is a military commission for Daniel Rathbun, Jr., signed by New York governor John Jay in 1798.
Scope and Content Note
Collection of maps, atlas pages, and documents, depicting the Western Hemisphere, globe, and regions of North America from the 16th to 18th centuries. Includes four maps drawn by Samuel Lewis (ca. 1854-1922) from "General Atlas of Guthrie's Geography Improved" by Matthew Carey. Also included is a military commission for Daniel Rathbun, Jr., signed by New York governor John Jay in 1798.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into two groupings by material type and sub-arranged alphabetically by creator or title.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Atlas Collection
Breed Collection of Maps, Documents, and Prints
Edward Lasker Collection of Atlases and Maps
Vassar College Archives Maps Collection
Subject Headings
Names:
Johnson, Guy, approximately 1740-1788; Lewis, Samuel, 1753 or 1754-1822; Münster, Sebastian, 1489-1552; Seutter, Matthäus, 1678-1757; Visscher, Nicolaes, 1649-1702
Places:
Massachusetts--Maps; New York (State)--Maps; North America--Maps; Pennsylvania--Maps; United States--Maps
Document Types:
Maps; Military commissions
VCL Categories:
Maps
Encoding Information
Encoded by Emma Gronbeck, September 2024.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mary Rathbone Acker, 2004 and 2005. [M2004-010 and M2005-003]
Container List
- MAPS
  - Johnson, Guy, "Map of the Frontiers of the Northern Colonies with the Boundary Line Established Between Them and the Indians at the Treaty Held by S. Will Johnson at Ft. Stanwyx in Nov. 1768," (Folder 1)
  - Lewis, Samuel, "British Possessions in North American (Map No. 23)," from "General Atlas of Guthrie's Geography Improved" by Matthew Carey, 1794 (Folder 2)
  - Lewis, Samuel, "State of Massachusetts (Map No. 28), from "General Atlas of Guthrie's Geography Improved" by Matthew Carey, 1795 (Folder 3)
  - Lewis, Samuel, "State of New York (Map No. 31), from "General Atlas of Guthrie's Geography Improved" by Matthew Carey, 1795 (Folder 4)
  - Lewis, Samuel, "State of Pennsylvania (Map No. 33), from "General Atlas of Guthrie's Geography Improved" by Matthew Carey, 1794 (Folder 5)
  - Munster, Sebastian, "Western Hemisphere,", 1550 (Folder 6)
  - Seutter, Matthew (Matthäus Seutter), "Diversi Globi Terr-Aque,", 1720 (Map Case - Drawer 32)
  - Visscher, Nicholas Janz (Nicolaes Visscher), "Novissima et Accuratissima, Titius Americae,", 1680 (Map Case - Drawer 32)
- DOCUMENTS
  - "Atlas Geographicus," descriptive folio including information about the Seutter map, 1720 (Folder 7)
  - "Commission of Daniel Rathbun," signed by New York governor John Jay, 1798 (Folder 8)